Guide to the George Y. Shevelov Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series I: Correspondence, 1950-2001
  - Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals, 1950-2001
    - Horniatkevych, A., Edmonton, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Horniatkevych, D., Irvington, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Horyn, Vasyl', L'viv, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Hoshovs'ka, Iaryna, Toronto, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Hoshovs'kyi, Bohdan, Toronto, undated, 1958-1984 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Hoshul's'kyi, Iosyp, Toronto, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Hrabovych: see Grabowicz, George G.
    - Hranovs'kyi, Oleksandr A. (aka Nepryts'kyi-Hranovs'kyi), London, St.Paul, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Hrozyk, Pavlo, L'viv, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Hrybins'ka, Svitlana, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Hryhorenko, Petro: see Grigorenko
    - Hrynchyshyn, Dmytro, L'viv, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Hryshko, Vasyl', Seattle, 1979-1980 (11 letters) (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Hrytsak, Alia, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Hrytsenko, Pavlo Iukhymovych, Kyiv, undated, 1989-2001 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Hubarzhevs'kyi, I., Wythall, 1954 1961 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Hudzovs'kyi, A.: see Gudzovs'kyi
    - Humenna, Dokiia, New York, undated, 1954-1989 (6 letters) (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Humets'ka, Asia, Ann Arbor, undated, 1975-1979 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Hundorova, Tamara, Kyiv, undated, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Huntley, D.G., Toronto, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Hurko, Stefaniia Gennadij (pseudonyms: Gwynt or Sofia Samotynska), Toronto, 1979-1985 (with her poetry attached) (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Hurs'kyi, Iakiv, Syracuse, 1950-1992 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Hüttl-Folter, Gerta (aka Huttl-Worth), various places, undated, 1962-1993 (40 letters and postcards, 2 letter fragments) (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Ianiv, Sofiia, Munich, Sarcelles, undated, 1951-1997 (Box 4, Folder 10 to 17)
    - Ianiv, Volodymyr, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - To George Shevelov, various places, undated, 1955-1983 (33 letters and postcards, 2 letter fragments)
      - To Kyrylo Mytrovych, Sarcelles, 1972 (1 letter)
    - Iar-M'iatka, Mariia, Terrywill, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Iasentseva, Mariia, 1977-1985 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Iashchun, Vasyl', Pittsburgh, 1970-1985 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Iashchyshyn, Oksana, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Il'chenko, Oles', Kyiv, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Il'nyts'kyi, Oleh, Cambridge, Winnipeg, 1978-1985 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Il'nyts'kyi, Roman, Philadelphia, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Iohansen, Alla, Munich, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Iohansen, Hai, 1950-1954 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Isachenko, Aleksandr V., Klagenfurt, 1971-1975 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Isaievych, Iaroslav, Cambridge, L'viv, 1989-1998 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Isaiv, Vsevolod, Toronto, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Iurchenko, Valentyna, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Ivakhniuk, Antin, Proton Station, 1981-1992 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Ivanenko, Leonid, Kyiv, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Ivchenko, Anatolii, Kharkiv, 1989-1998 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Ivchenko, L., 1950-1966 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Ivita, Pavel and Milka, 1958-1986 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Izars'kyi, Oleksa, 1950-1996 (260 letters and postcards, 1 copy of reply) (Box 5, Folder 4 to 8)
    - Jacobsson, Gunnar, Goteborg, 1957-1976 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Jakobson, Roman, Cambridge, MA, 1951-1957 (10 letters, some with carbon replies) (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Jagoditsch, Rudolf, Vienna, 1952-1954 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Kachaluba, M., 1987 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Kachurovs'kyi, Ihor, undated, 1979-1983 (16 letters, 1 photocopy of radioscript dedicated to Shevelov's 75 anniversary) (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Kalashovych, Volodymyr, Kharkiv, 1994-1999 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Kalytovs'ka, Marta, Sarcelles, Somizha, 1956-1982 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Kantor, Marvin, Ann Arbor, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Karnaushenko, Halyna, Kharkiv, 1991-1994 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Karpovich, Mikhail Mikhailovich, Cambridge, MA, 1951 1953 (2 letters) (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Kasinec, Edward, Cambridge, Berkeley, 1977-1983 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Kaskiv, Volodymyr A., Willimantic, CT, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Kasyns'kyi, Pavlo, Munich, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Keis, Vitalii, 1978 (2 letters) (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Kende, Pierre, Paris, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Kentrzhyns'kyi, Bohdan, Stockholm, 1950-1980 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Kerch, Oksana, Philadelphia, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Khandamirova, Irina, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Kharchun, Iaroslav, Toronto, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Khats'ko, Tymofii Hryhorovych, Donets'k region, Tsukuryno, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Khobzei, Natalia, L'viv, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Khodun, Ievhen, Kharkiv, 1996 2000 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Khoshkevych, Halyna Hnativna, France, 1989-1999 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Khotkevych, Halyna: see Kots'
    - Kiparskaia, Dagmara, Helsinki, 1957 1975 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Kiparskii, Valentyn, various places, 1961-1975 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Kis, Teofil I., Ottawa University, 1981-1984 (re: Simovych publication) (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Kleiner, Izrail, Jerusalem, 1978-1987 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Klekh, Volodyslav, New Rochelle, NJ, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Klenin, Emily, California, 1986 1988 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Klymovs'kyi, Iaroslav, Philadelphia, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Klynovyi, Iurii: see Stefanyk, Iurii
    - Knysh, Irena, Norwood, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Knysh, Iurii, Winnipeg, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Kobusashi, Masanari, Krakow, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Kochur, Andrii, Kyiv, 1995-1998 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Kod(?)ba, Ostap, Paris, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Kohut, Zenon, Cambridge, MA, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Kolens'ka, Liuba, Irvington, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Kolesov, V., Yale University, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Koliankivs'kyi, Mykola and Olia, Niagara Falls, 1981-1986 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Kolisnyk, Roman, Toronto, 1985-1986 (including copy of Iurii Stefanyk's letter of 1984) (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Kolomyiets', Iurii (aka George), Chicago, 1979-1981 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Kolosiv, Washington, DC, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Koneski, Blaže, Skopje, undated, 1964-1983 (25 letters and postcards, 1 note. Some with carbon replies) (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Konetschny, Rudolf and Maria, Munich, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Kononenko, Petro, Kyiv, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Kopecny, Frantisek, Prostejov-Vrahovice, 1950s-1975 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Korbutiak, D.M., 1980 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Korchyns'ka-Iefremova, Halyna, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Kornieienko, Agneshka, Krakow, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Korniienko, Nelli, Moscow, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Korohods'kyi, Roman, Kyiv, 1993-2000 (Box 6, Folder 9 to 11)
    - Korol', Oleksandr, Zaporizhzhia, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Koropetrs'kyi, Ivan, Philadelphia, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Korotych, Vitalii Oleksiiovych, no place, 1967 (1 postcard) (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Korovyts'kyi, Ivan, Kerhonkson, NY, undated, 1978-1985 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Kosach, Iurii, New York, 1953-1979 (3 letters) (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Koshelivets', Ivan, Munich, undated, 1952-1993 (98 letters and postcards, some with carbon replies) (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Koshmider, Erwin, undated, Munich, 1950-1977 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Kosovycheva, M., Terryville, 1954-1955 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Kostiuk, Hryhorii, undated, 1950-2000 (see also Subseries I.2: Correspondence with Organizations--"Slovo", Box 16, Folder 13) (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Kostiuk, Oleksandra F., Minneapolis, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Kostruba, Petro Petrovych, L'viv, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Kots', Mariian, New York, Kharkiv, 1983-2000 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Kovaliv, P., New York, 1956-1969 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Koverko, Oleh, Chicago, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Kozak, Stefan, Warsaw, 1975 1992 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Koznars'kyi, Taras, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Krachkivs'kyi, B., Detroit, undated, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Krajcovic, Rudolf, Bratislava, 169-1974 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Kramarchuk, Eryka, Jersey City, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Krasykov, Mykhailo M., 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Kravchenko, Bohdan, Edmonton, Toronto, 1979-1987 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Kravs, Orest, Syracuse, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Kravtsiv, Bohdan, Rutherford, 1975 (1 letter) (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Kriachkiv, Petro, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Krupnytskyi, B., Himmelpforten, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Krushel'nyts'ka, Lidiia, New York, undated, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Kryzanowska, Zofia, Warsaw, 1958-1967 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Kryzanowski, Julian, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Kubiiovych, Volodymyr, Sarcelles, 1952-1984 (50 letters and postcards) (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Kucera, Henry, New York, Providence, 1957 1966 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Kuhn, Hans, Canberra, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Kundera, Milan, no place, 1979 to B.Hrybinsky (1 letter; photocopy with carbon replies) (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Kupchyns'kyi, Oleh, L'viv, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Kurashkiewicz, Wladislaw, Poznan, 1967-1993 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Kurilova, Liudmila, L'viv, undated, 1959-1991 (see also related letters from Marchenko, Lidiia in Box 8, Folder 21) (Box 7, Folder 5 to 9)
    - Kurinna, R., Munich, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Kurpil', Ol'ha, Albany, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Kuryms'kyi, A., Prague, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Kutsenko, Leonid, Kirovohrad, 1994,1995 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Kutsiuk, Magdalena, Bucharest, undated, 1973-1995 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Kuzelia, Zenon, Munich, 1950-1952 (4 letters and postcards) (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Kyrychuk, Nadiia, Kurytyba, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Kysilevs'kyi, Kost', undated, 1952 1961 (4 letters, 1 extract from letter, 1 invitation) (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Kyslytsia, Dmytro, various places, 1952-1988 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Labun'ka, Myroslav, Philadelphia, 1974 1979 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Lapins'ka, Janina, Krakow, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Lawrynenko, Jurij, various places, undated, 1950-1979 (60 letters and postcards, some with carbon replies) (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Lawrynenko Family (Marusia, Lesia, Mykola), New York, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Ledkovskaia, Marina Viktorovna, 1977-1998 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Lednitskii, V., Berkeley, 1953-1967 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Leed, Richard L., Ithaca, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Leeming, Henry H. and Katie, undated, 1972 1975 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Lehfeldt, Werner, Konstanz, undated, 1984-1988 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Lesiv, Mykhailo, Lublin, 1964-1999 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Leska, Oldrich, Prague, undated, 1957-1997 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Lesych, Vadym, 1955 1979 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Levseichuk, New York, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Levyts'kyi, Borys, Munich, 1979-1981 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Liaturyns'ka, Oksana, undated, 1953-1956 (11 letters, 1 letter fragment, 1 poem, 1 note) (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Lightner, Theodore M., Cambridge, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Lindheim, Ralph, Toronto, undated, 1988 1990 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Liston, Jerry, various places, undated, 1965-1972 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Livyts'ka-Kholodna, Natalia, no place, undated, 1978-1993 (15 letters and postcards; poems) (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Lobiuc, Ioan, Romania, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Lopez-Morillas, Martin, Moscow, New York, 1966 1970 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Lord, Albert Bates (Mr. and Mrs.), 1954 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Lorriman, T., Ottawa, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Lozyns'kyi, Askol'd, New York, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Luckyj, George Stephen Nestor (aka Iurii Luc'kyi), Toronto, undated, 1953-1997 (342 letters and postcards; some with carbon replies and clippings) (Box 8, Folder 6 to 11)
    - Lundstrom, Goran, Lund, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Lunt, Horace Gray, Cambridge, MA, 1954-1957 (9 letters; some with carbon replies) (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Lupul, Manoly R., Edmonton, 1976-1985 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Lutsiv, V.O., Pennsylvania University, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Lyman, Leonid, no place, undated, 1951 (2 letters) (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Lypa, Marta (aka Lypa-Humenets'ka), 1996 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Lysenko, Ivan Maksymovych, Kyiv, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Lysiak-Rudnyts'kyi, Ivan, various places, 1953-1984 (18 letters) (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - McMillin, Arnold B., Liverpool, 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Machek, V., Brno, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Magiste, Julius, Lund, 1955 1963 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Magner, Thomas F., Pennsylvania University, 1966-1978 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Magnusson, Walter L., Reykjavik, 1977-1980 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Magocsi, Paul R., Cambridge, MA, 1978-1985 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Maguire, Robert A., 1998 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Maistrenko, Ivan, Munich, 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Makaiev, E., 1964 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Makarenko, Vladimir, Paris, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Malanchuk, Ol'ha, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Maliar, Pavlo, Syracuse, 1952-1979 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Malmstad, J.E., Berkeley, undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Malyts'kyi, Oleksander, Cincinnati, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Marchenko, Lidiia Efimovna, L'viv, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Marchenko, P., 1978 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Mares, F.V., Austria, 1969,1973 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Margolina-Hansen, Liubov, various places, 1967-1979 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Markade, V.D., Paris, 1977-1988 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Markov, V., undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Markus', Vasyl', Chicago, 1980-1994 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Martin, Richard, Pennsylvania University, 1966 1972 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Martinet, André, Seine, 1955-1968 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Martsiuk, Khrystyna, Munich, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Maru(?), Zynovii, Munich, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Marunchak, Mykhailo, Winnipeg, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Marusyk, Taras, Kyiv, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Marvan, Irzi, Davis, CA; Melbourne, 1969-1991 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Masenko, Larysa, 1990-2000 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Masidoff, Robert, New York, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Matejka, Ladislav (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Mathiassen, Terje, Oslo, 1986-1989 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Mathiesen Robert, undated, 1966-1982 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Matthews, W.K., London, 1950-1957 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Matviienko, Petro, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Mauser, Jadwiga, Berkeley, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Mazon, André, Paris, 1951-1967 (16 letters and postcards, some with carbon replies; 1 invitation) (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Mel'nyk, Volodymyr Oleksandrovych, Kyiv, Kharkiv, 1990-1996 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Mel'nyk, Z. Lew, Cincinnati, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Miegel, Warsaw, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Mihajlov, Mikajlo, Beograd, 1979 (1 letter) (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Miiakovs'kyi, Volodymyr, New York, 1954-1969 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Milewski, Tadeusz, Krakow, 1958 1960 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Mirchuk, Ivan, Munich, 1950-1957 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Moisejiene, Jolanta, Kaunas, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Moiseius, Liubomyr, Kaunas, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Molnar, Mykhailo, Bratislava, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Monyriski, Lehen, Torun, 1970-1977 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Moroz, Myron, Sudbury, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Moroz, Myroslav, L'viv, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Moroz, Raisa, Winnipeg, 1980 1987 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Moroz, Valentyn Iakovych, Passaic, 1980 (1 letter) (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Mosely, Philip Edward, New York, 1952 (1 telegram, 1 carbon reply) (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Moser, Charles A., New Haven, Washingto DC, 1962-179 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Movcha(?), Chicago, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Moyle, Natalie K., Charlottesville, 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Mukhyna, Halyna, Winnipeg, 1987 1988 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Muromtsev, Ihor Viktorovych, 1990-1999 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Muromtseva, O.H., 1990-1999 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Murphy, David, Saint Louis, MO, 1971-1987 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Mushynka, Mykola, 1988-1995 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Muzychka, I., Rome, 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Mykhailovych, Urbana, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Mykhalevych, Ihor, Philadelphia, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Mykhalevych, M., Philadelphia, 1980-1983 (6 letters) (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Myshuha, L., Jersey City1952-1954 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Mytrovych, Kyrylo, 1969-1972 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Nadraga, Vasyl', Washington DC, 1974 1983 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Nadson, Aleksander, London, 1972-1979 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Nahtigal, R., Ljubljana, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Nakonechna, Hanna, various places, 1951-1981 (97 letters and postcards; 4 letter fragments) (Box 9, Folder 23 to 24)
    - Naum'iak, Pylyp, France, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Naydan, Michael M., 1977-1994 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Nedil'ko, Ol., 1978 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Nemyra, Kateryna, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Nepryts'kyi-Hranovs'kyi, Oleksandr: see Hranovs'kyi
    - Neshcheret, Tetiana, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Nestna, Olena, undated (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Newman, Lawrence W., Columbus, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Nicholson, John Greer, Montreal, 1970 1971 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Niniovs'kyi, V., Edmonton, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Nosko, B. and J., 1977 undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Novovirs'kyi, N., New York, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Novyts'kyi, Sviatoslav, St.Paul, MN, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Nowell, Liza, (nee Tetiievskaia), 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Nytchenko, Dmytro (aka Chub), Newport, 1979-1998 (39 letters and postcards) (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Nyzakivs'kyi, B., Detroit, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Obozbska-Jablonska, Antonina, Warsaw, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Obolenskii, Dmitrii Dmitrievich, New Haven, 1957 (2 letters; 1 carbon reply) (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Odarchenko, Petro, various places, 1952-2000 (42 letters and postcards; 1 carbon reply) (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Odmark, John, Hamburg, 1976-1977 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Ohloblyn, Oleksander Petrovych, Ludlow, 1953-1978 (35 letters and postcards; some with carbon replies; 1 note) (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Okhrimenko, Nina: see her letter of 12 July 1994 in Oksana Solovii's Correspondence (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Okinshevych, Lev Oleksandrovych, New York, 1950-1952 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Oleksandriv, Borys, 1975-1979 (See also: Subseries I.2: Correspondence with Organizations--"Slovo", Box 16, Folder 13) (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Oleksiichuk, Leonid Iu., 1979 1987 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Olesch, R., Köln, 1963-1986 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Olesiiuk, T., Texas, 1953 1954 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Olmsted, Hugh M., Cambridge, MA, 1988 1989 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Onyshkevych, Larysa: see Zales'ka-Onyshkevych
    - Oriam, Iurii, Montreal, 1980 1981 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Ornstein, Jacob, El Paso, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Osadcha, Tania, Troy, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Osadchuk, Bohdan, Munich, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Osakiwsky, Ihor, Toronto, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Osinchuk, Roman, New York, 1955 1969 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Os'machka, Todos', no place, undated, 1954 (2 letters, 1 carbon reply) (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Ostakhevs'kyi, Roman, Edmonton, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Ostrowski, Donald, 1981 1983 (including his publication "Textual criticism and the Povest' vremennykh let: some theoretical considerations") (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Ovcharenko, Mariia, 1958-1982 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Ozerov, N., 1976 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Padokh, Iaroslav, 1952-1989 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Palii, Lida, Toronto, 1969-1992 (17 letters) (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Pan'ko, Serhii, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Pavlovs'ka, S., South Bound Brook, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Pavlych, M., Kyiv, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Pavlychko, Dmytro Vasyl'ovych, 1968 (1 postcard) (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Pavlychko, Solomiia, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Pavlyshyn, Marko, Australia, 1994-1998 (9 letters and postcards) (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Pazuniak, Nataliia, 1969 1985 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Pecheniuk, Volodymyr, Tehran, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Pelens'kyi, Iaroslav, 1960-1978 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Pennington, Anne E., Oxford, 1973-1976 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Perfets'kyi, Iurii, Philadelphia, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Petrenko, Maia: see Gregoret
    - Petrenko, Pavlo, 1950 1953 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Pevnyi, Bohdan, New York, Kyiv, 1978-2000 (7 letters and postcards) (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Picchio, Riccardo, 1966-1975 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Pidhainyi, Semen, Detroit, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Pirogov, S., Munich, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Pliushch, Leonid, undated, 1982-1996 (Box 10, Folder 23 to 26)
    - Pliushch, Tetiana, undated, 1979-1996 (Box 10, Folder 23 to 26)
    - Pocheptsov, Georgii Georgievich, Kyiv, 1966-1990 (11 letters) (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Pohorilyi, Semen, Winnipeg, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Pohrebennyk, Fedir, Kyiv, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Pohribnyi, A., Kyiv, undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Polański, Kazimierz, Krakow, 1963-1986 (5 letters and postcards) (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Poltava, Leonid, 1952-1957 (7 letters and postcards) (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Poltavchenko-Lytva(?), Halyna, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Pomerantsev, Igor', 1979-1984 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Ponedilok, Mykola, New York, undated, 1953-1968 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Pop, Sever, Lund, 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Pope, Richard, undated, 1967-1968 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Popiv, Iurii, Fort Vein, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Popova, K., Fort Vein, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Popovych, Ievhen, undated, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Press, J. Ian, London, 1970-1990 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Pribic, Nikola, Austin, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Priestly, Tom, 1976-1979 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Pritsak, Omeljan, various places, 1950-1983 (44 letters and postcards; 1 carbon reply; 1 note) (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Prokop, Myroslav, New York, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Prosen, Emil, Stocholm, 1951 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Protsiuk, Stepan G., New York, 1961-1983 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Pryliu, Vira Hryhorivna, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Prysiazhnyi, Mykhailo, L'viv, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Pshenychnyi, Ievhen, Drohobych, 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Puda, Petro, St.Paolo, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Pylypiuk, Natalia, Cambridge, MA, 1978-1990 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Pytlar, Orest B., New York, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Pyziur, Eugene, St.Luis, 1967 (1 letter) (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Raeff, Marc, 1988 (1 letter) (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Regush, K.: see his letter of 1976 to Oldrich Leska in Leska's correspondence (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Rehder, Peter, Munich, 1978-1996 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Reichling, Anton, Amsterdam, 1954- (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Rensky, MIroslav, New York, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Reod, Allen Walker, New York, 1971-1973 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Revuts'kyi, V., 1955-1980 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Riabchuk, Mykola, Kyiv, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Riegler, Jacob, 1970-2001 (Box 11, Folder 8 to 9)
    - Rivy, 1957 1960 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Rodezky, Irwin, 1970 1997 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Roik, O., New Westminster, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Rohovs'kyi, K., Etobicoke, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Roizenzon, Leonid, Samarkand, undated, 1964-1969 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Romanenchuk, B., 1950 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Romanenko, Hlib, Montreal, undated, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Romanyshyn, Oleh, Toronto, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Romashko, A., 1950 1952 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Rothe, Hans, Bonn, 1983-1989 (Box 11, Folder 13)